是他们吗？
Is that them?
天啊，他们在这就地裁员么？
Jesus Christ. Are they going to do it right here?
你们之前没见过种事？
Have you guys ever been through this before?
没有。
- No.
最好忽视他们的存在，低头做你的事。
it's best to ignore it. Keep your head down...go back to work.
去吧。
Go on.
别偷看。
Don't watch!
蒂蒙西・欣？
Timothy Singh?
是我。
Yes.
我们得和你谈谈。
I'm afraid we have to speak with you.
埃里克・戴尔？
Eric Dale?
-什么？  -埃里克・戴尔？
- Excuse me?    - Eric Dale?
-呃，不是。 -什么？
-Er, no.   -Sorry?
我不是戴尔。
I'm not Eric Dale.
哦，对不起。
Oh. I'm so sorry.
他是我上司，在走廊那头办公。
He's my boss, he's down the hall.
谢了。
Thanks.
不好意思，戴尔先生？
Excuse me? Mr. Dale?
过来一下。
This way.
来了。
Okay.
我很抱歉…
I'm obviously sorry ...
我们今天来这里
that we are here today;
可现在是特殊时期，你一定也明白。
but these are extra ordinary times as you very well must know.
听着，我负责风险管理部
Look, I run risk management...
我不觉得这个部门是可以裁员的地方。
I don't really see, how that's a natural place to start cutting jobs.
请你明白这里没有私人恩怨。
We hope you understand that this is in no way personal.
这层楼的大部分人今天都要被炒
The majority of this floor is being let go today.
我们要向你讲清楚
Ms. Bratberg is now going to
公司提供赔偿的详细方案。
run through the details of what the firm is offering.
戴尔先生，公司赔偿你三个月工资
Mr. Dale the firm is offering you six months severance,at half your salary.
你可以保留现在手中的所有期货合同。
You will keep all unvested options that you currently hold.
健康保险届时就会到期。
Health will be extended through that period.
你要在明天4:47之前决定
You have till tomorrow at... 4:47
接受公司的方案，否则这些福利就被废除。
to either take the offer or it will be revoked.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
明白。
Yes.
不幸的是，由于你的工作有非常高的机密性
Unfortunately Mr. Dale, due to the highly sensitive nature of your work here
公司必须要做出相对谨慎的一些行动，
the firm has to take certain precautions
也许有些会让你觉得有所冒犯。
for security purposes that may seem punitive in nature.
你已经为公司工作了19年，我希望，
I hope considering your...over 19 years of service to the firm,
你应该理解，公司的这些行为
you will understand that these measures are in no way..
绝非对你的工作或者人格有任何不满。
a reflection of the firm's feelings towards your performance or your character.
-我不明白。-她在向你道歉，
- I don't understand.  - She's apologizing...
为接下来的事情道歉。
for what's about to happen.
你的公司邮箱，服务器许可
Your company email, access to the server,
还有大楼的通行证，手机数据及服务
access to the building, and your mobil data and phone service
在本会议结束后都会终止。
will all be severed as of this meeting.
这位先生会带你回到办公室，
And, This gentleman, will take you to your office.
陪同你整理私人物品。
So, you can clear out your personal belongings.
那我手头的事情怎么办？
What about the.. what I'm currently working on?
有些事我正做到一半。-公司已经有了移交计划，
I'm in the middle of something...  - The firm has worked out
也准备好了怎么继续下去
its transition plan.and is prepared to move forward,
但是还是要感谢你能考虑到这些。
But, we do we appreciate your concern.
我们知道这很难让人接受，这是我的名片
We understand that this is very difficult and here is my card.
如果在接下来的几周内，
Please contact me over the next few weeks,
你对这一重大转变需要任何帮助，请联系我。
If you'd any assistence with this transition in your life.
遗憾不能共事了。
I'm sorry.
-你没被炒？ -目前没有。
-Are you still alive? - Uh huh..For now.
恭喜。
Congratulations.
形势严峻哪。-我听说了。
It's a bloodbath.  - I heard.
听着，埃里克
Listen Eric?
要是我能帮你留住职位，我肯定会那么做。
If there was something I could have done, I'd have done it.
-我知道你会的。 -我肯定会。
-I know. -All right? -Yeah. I know. -Ok.
-告诉我是谁要我走？-噢拜托
-Just tell me...Who was it? -...Come on.
-罗杰斯？ -我不会选边站，你懂的。
-Come on, Will. Rogers? - I'm not gonna side, you know me.
罗伯特森？
Robertson?
臭娘们。我就知道，我去年就该去找她的。
That cunt. I knew it. I never should have gone to her last year.
没人要你走，只是你运气不好。仅此而已。
Look it wasn't anyone. It was bad luck. And that's all it was.
好吧，祝好运。
Alright, Well...Good luck.
近前说话。我这里个破事儿干到一半，
Come here. I was just in the middle of a lot of shit right here
最好有人来看一看。
that I think somebody need to take a look at.
埃里克 听着
Eric Listen...
他们说所有人都不许进来，不许碰这里的东西。
They are telling us that everybody needs to get out of here and just leave this.
感谢你的关心，但是这工作不再是你的问题了。
And while we appreciate your concern, but it's not your problem anymore.
祝你好运。
Good luck.
埃里克，我们为你难过。
Eric, I am very sorry. - Yeah.
他们会炒了我们吗？
Did they say what was going to happen with us?
拜托，塞斯。
Jesus Seth. - What?
这里最近会一直这样糟乱
It's gonna get pretty ugly around here for a while..
但你们应该没事。
but you guys will be alright.
我们回头见，好吗？-好。
I'll be seeing you around. - Alright.
谢谢。
Thank you.
我想对你说声谢谢。
I just wanted to say thanks.
-没这个必要。-有的。
-That's not neccessary. - Well, it is.
从你这里，我学到了很多… -我懂得。
You were the person around here, that I.. - I know.
有个事情我做了一半，他们不让我继续干了。
Look,I was working on something But they wouldn't let me finish it.
你看看吧。
So, take a look at it.
小心点。
Be careful.
罗伯特森？莎拉・罗伯特森？
Robertson? Sarah Robertson?
莎拉!
Sarah!
你把我手机停了？
You shut off my phone?
埃里克，我什么都没做。
Eric, I didn't do anything.
扯淡！
Fuck you!
人心惶惶啊。
It's fucking hedious.
总是要先变糟了才能变好。
It's gonna get worse before it gets better.
-是么？ -总是如此。
-You think?  -Much.
有烟么？
You got any Nicorettes?
我没烟了。
I'm out of Nicorettes.
也就是说…
Which means, in about..
10分钟内我要抓狂了。
Ten minutes. I'm gonna kill someone.
你没事吧，山姆？
You alright Sam?
我的狗快死了。
My dog is dying.
真..遗憾
I'm sorry?
刚打电话给兽医，
Just got a phone to the vet,
她的肝上长了个肿瘤。
it's some fucking tumor on her liver.
为了让她活着我每天都得花一千美元。
I must've paid almost a thousand bucks a day already, just to keep her alive.
我不知道还该怎么办，威尔。
and I don't have a fucking clue what to do about it.
他们都…走了。
Well they're all gone.
那…
So?
我们还剩下多少人？
How many do we have left?
大概33个。
About, Thirty-three.
把他们都叫到外头来，我得说点什么。
Make sure everyone is out there, I gotta say something.
他们都准备好了，等着你呢。
Yeah, I know. They are ready. They're ready for you.
好了，掌声响起！
Alright, Let's hear it!
你们留下来是有原因的
You are all still here for a reason...
这层楼80%的人都离开了，不会再回来。
eighty percent of this floor was just sent home...forever.
我们刚花了一个小时和他们说再见。
We have spent the last hour saying our good-byes...
他们都是好人，他们都干得不错
they were good people and they were good at their jobs...
但你们做得更好。
but you all were better.
现在他们走了，这里不会有人去再想到他们。
Now they are gone. They are not to be thought of again.
这是你们的机遇。
This is your opportunity.
这栋楼的所有楼层，从香港到伦敦的
On every floor of this building and in every office
所有办公室，都在发生同样的事
from Hong Kong to London the same thing is happening.
等这些都结束了
By the time we are done..
你距离你的上一级职位
3 of every seven guys;
会少掉七分之三的竞争对手。
who were standing between you and your boss's job...are gone.
这就是你们的机遇。
That is your opportunity.
我在这里工作了34年。
I've been at this place for thirty-four years.
告诉你们，这不会是你们最后一次经历这样的事。
I can tell you that this will not be the last time you're gonna go through this.
但你们都是幸存者。
But you are all survivors...
这也就是为什么这家公司在107年之后
And that is how this firm over 107 years,
还越来越壮大。
has continued to grow stronger.
所以保持高调，回去工作吧。掌声响起~
So, keep your heads high...and get back to work. Let's hear it.
大家都走了，你也走吧。
Everyone is going out man...you should come on.
我没事。
Oh, I'm cool. Thanks.
好吧，如果你改主意了，给我打电话。
Okay. Well, if you change your mind, jut give me a call.
我会的。
I Will.
来吧！
Come!
你们去哪儿？-大地酒吧。
Where are you guys going? - The Grand.
我干完了给你打电话。
I'll call you when I'm done.
嘿，我们留下来了，高兴点。
Hey, Be glad, you're still alive.
高兴呢。
I am.
喂？
Yeah, Hello.
我听不见。
I can't hear you.
你能出去说吗？你那太吵了。
Can you go outside, It's too loud.
等一下，我出去接。
Hold on a second, it's, well, just give me a second.
怎么了？
All right. What's up?
你们在哪儿？ -大地酒吧。
Where are you? - Lugo.
威尔在吗？-威尔・艾默生？
Are you with Will? - Yeah, Will Emerson?
他应该还在，怎么了？
Yeah, I think he's still here. Why?
好吧我要你和威尔一起回来。
I need you to get Will and I need you guys to come back up here.
呃，回哪儿？ -办公室。
Uh, Where? - To the office.
- 什么？ - 没开玩笑。
- What? - I'm serious.
你要我把咱们上司的上司
Wait a sec. You want me to get our boss's boss out of
在周四晚上10点钟从酒吧弄回公司？
a club and bring him back to the office...at 10:00 on a Thursday night?
咱们上司被解雇了，理论上说他是咱的直属上司，
Our boss just got axed,so technically he is our boss,
所以是的，我的确要这么做。
and yes that's what I want you to do.
为啥？
Why?
听着哥们儿，相信我，好吗？我要你们现在回来。
Look man, Just trust me okay. I need you guys back here, now.
好吧，10分钟赶到。
Alright, we'll be there in ten.
我对你提起你背面有多美么
Have I ever told you how much I love your back?
真的。你有试过易装么？
Really. Do you have a little dress-and-match.. Is it?
你能像美妞一样跳舞.
You could dance around it like a fucking girl.
嘿，看看谁在开夜工哪。
Hey, look who it is, burning the candleat both ends.
为什么你不一起出去玩？
Why didn't you come out with us?
又没有其他的裁员计划，你不用拍我马屁。
There's no more cuts planned. You don't have to kiss my arse.
说真的,我其实不明白你们做的工作。
I frankly, don't even know, what it is you guys do.
威尔我很抱歉让你们回办公室。- 没关系。
Will, I am so sorry I had to bring you guys back..- That's alright.
-肿么了？ -看这个。
-What's going on? -Look at this.
埃里克走之前给我这个文件。
Eric gave me this file before he left.
他说他还没有完成全部的计算
And he told me he couldn't quite figure it out,
电梯门快关上前，他对我说的最后一句话是“小心点”。
And the last thing he says as the doors on the elevator close is be careful.
他说小心点？- 对，我有点好奇，所以就打开看了。
He said, Be careful?- Yeah, So..obviously..I'm little curious.
然后我就继续他的研究，发现这里的亏空…
I get into it a bit and I realize that the only thing missing..
大事不好了，威尔。
This is not good, Will.
什么大事不好了
So. What is this doing here?
用模式四，这样看着更明白。
Go to model four, it makes more sense.
这是什么？
What is this?
这基本上是我们帐下的所有东西。
This is basically everything that we have in our books.
任意特定时间的账目。埃里克试图演示
At any given time. But what Eric was trying to do
这些数据在标准预计亏损模型以外的波动情况，
is to work this numbers for levers of volatility
这种情况下需要以不同杠杆值计算。
that fall outside of our standard VAR model.
什么杠杆？
What are those levers?
这…有点复杂… -那就简化！
Well it's a fairly complicated... - Simplify.
这些杠杆基本是由历史数据确定
The volatility levers are set using..historic patterns basically,
然后再按粗略的10%-15%的分级设置。
and then stretching those patterns out on a 10-15%... roughly.
好吧，然后呢？- 然后我们开始测试那些证券的走势。
Alright, So? - So, We are starting to test those historic patterns.
什么时候的？
When?
今天
Today?
周一
Monday...
还有上周五和周三。- 还有两周之前的周五。
Last friday and wednesday.. - Two Fridays ago.
好吧，我明白了。
Alright, I get it.
尼马，这个曲线方向反了吧，这…
Fuck me. Once this thing gets going in the wrong direction...
亏大发了。-有多大？
It's huge.   - How huge?
损失好像比公司目前的市值还高…
The losses are greater than the current value of the company...
这是项目，光是项目上的损失，威尔。
Projected... Projected losses... Will.
只是我们这层的？- 没错。
This is just our floor?- Yes.
埃里克・戴尔在哪儿呢？
Where the fuck is Eric Dale?
不知道，我试过联系他，但是他关机了。
I don't know. Tried to call him, his phone's off.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他们把被裁的人的手机都停了。
They turned off everyone's phone who they axed today.
没心没肺。你打的是他的私人电话？
Fucking ruthless. You tried his personal cell?
是啊，他的手机，没开。
Yeah, I called the cellphone, it's not on!
给他家里打电话。- 在这个点儿？
Call his home. - At this hour?
对，你确定他是正确的吗？- 我看他对着呢。
Yeah... Do we even know if he's right? - Looks pretty fucking right to me.
戴尔夫人，我是威尔・艾默生。
Mrs. Dale. This is Will Emerson.
我很好，谢谢。能叫下埃里克吗？
I'm fine, thank you. May I speak with Eric?
找不到，我们试过了，他手机关机了。
No, we've tried that. His phone appears to be off.
你能让他给我打电话吗？
Listen, could you have him call me?
他一回来... 一进门就让他给我打。
The moment he comes in... the moment he walks through the door.
谢谢你，再见。
Thank you so much. Goodbye.
- 他丫的去哪儿了？- 他好像有三个孩子。 - 所以呢？
- Where the fuck is he? - Doesn't he have like three kids?  - So?
我不知道，你有三个孩子的话你会不回家吗？
I don't know, would you go home?
我知道他去哪儿了。
I know where he is.
你们俩去接他。
I need you two, to go and get him.
楼下会有车等你们，去吧。
There will be a car waiting for you downstairs. You need to go.
- 现在？- 没错，现在。
- Right now?- Yeah, Right now.
- 你要去干什么？- 我给山姆打电话。
- What are you going to do? - I'm gonna call, Sam.
完蛋了。
Fuck me.
- 喂？ - 我威尔。
- Yes? - It's Will.
现在是夜里11点。
It's 11 O'clock at night?
-我知道，本来不会这时候给你打电话… -怎么了?
-I know I'm sorry. I wouldn't have called... -What's the problem?
我想你该回趟公司。
I think you need to get back here.
现在可是夜里11点！
What? It's 11 O'clock at night!
我知道现在是几点！
I'm well aware of the fucking time!
山姆，你得来看看这个。
Sam, I'm telling you..You need to see this.
看什么啊？
See what?
发邮件给我。
Email it to me.
我觉得那不是个好主意。
I don't think that would be a good idea.
好吧我来了。
I'm on my way.
看看这些人。
Look at these people.
在这瞎逛荡，根本不知道要发生什么了。
Wandering around, with absolutely no idea..what's about to happen.
对么？- 我试着不去那么想。
Right? - Well, I try not to let work get to me like that.
我就知道你没那脑子
I've noticed that about you.
行了别逗了，我们才23岁。- 我28了。
Look, we are twenty three years old... - I'm 28.
我去年赚了差不多25万美元。
I made nearly, a quarter of a million dollars last year...
卧勒个去，为了什么？就为了把数据码在电脑屏幕上
Fuck! for what...? Pushing some numbers around on a computer screen,
一帮高傲的傻逼
so a bunch of glorified crack addicts
拿过这些数据，假装什么都懂
could take that information and pretend to understand it,
然后再拿这些数据去忽悠全世界的
and then make a bet against some other jock
其它穷蛋。天知道，他们如果不被这个忽悠
half way around the world who if he..wasn't doing this,
可能会把钱放赛马场赌7号什么的。
he'd be putting number seven or you know?
最后总是有人赢也有人输。
And at the end of the day one guy win and the other guy loses.
你知道实际上比这个要复杂得多，对吧？
You do know it's a little more complicated than that?
没错。
Yeah.
是威尔。要是问我们有没有找到，怎么说？
It's Will. He wants to know if we've found him? What do we say?
就说…还没找到他呢。
I would say...that we haven't found him, Yet.
埃里克・戴尔的数据…
Eric Dale...
在他由那个讨厌的保安看着离开大楼的时候…
Before he leaves the building, escorted by fucking security...
-这跟我没关系。-没说你有。
-I had nothing to do with that. -I know.
抱歉。继续说。
I'm sorry. Go on.
他离开之前把他的一个U盘给了皮特・沙利文
Before he leaves the building he hands a disk to Peter Sullivan...
谁是皮特・沙利文？
Who's Peter Sullivan, again?
别管那么多了，戴尔的下属。
Don't matter, One of Eric's guys.
在电梯门关上之前
Before, the elevator doors are closing..
他说的最后一句话是
The last thing he says is...
“小心点”
'Be Careful'
“小心点”？- 没错。- 什么意思？
'Be Careful'? - Yeah. - Why?
看看这个。
Take a look.
哦天啊，你知道我看不懂这个。直接告诉我吧。
You know i can't read this fucking thing! Speak to me in English.
这个叫皮特・沙利文的小子
Basically, this kid, Peter Sullivan..
因为你的激励，顺便说一句，你讲的确实不错
He gets all inspired by you pep talk, Nice job! By the way..
下班之后他还埋头苦干，
He dealt straight in, after work.
现在他是板上钉钉了。- 找到了什么？
And I think he nailed it. - Nailed it?
他找到了埃里克在找的问题。
Yeah, I think he figured out what Eric was missing.
看上去不妙了，山姆。
...it‘s not good, Sam.
这些是…
These here are the...
股市上历史数据的指标限制，
historical volatility index limits, which of course,
是我们系统风险分析的主要依据…
our entire trading model relies on pretty fucking heavily...
我们现在很大程度上都依赖这个指标。
And well, we are now so levered up.
但是当这些数据都超过预警之后，
But once it gets outside those limits
事情就变得很糟糕了。
it gets ugly in a hurry.
我们离预警限制有多近？
And how close to those limits have we gotten?
哦山姆，我们超过了预警…
Oh Sam, we're beyond close...
之前的两周里，我们已经冲破这些
We broke through five or six days over the last two weeks,
预警限制5、6次了
Now somehow, we've managed
现在暂时又回到了限制区域内… -暂时？
to stay on the upside  of it...for now. -For now?
你看，这是如果我们超到极值之外会发生的事。
Well look.. what happens here when we get on the wrong side of it.
等一下，我该看什么？
Wait a minute. What am I looking at?
看这儿的数字。
You're looking at this figure here.
额…这个是？- 没错。
Wow...is that? - Yeah.
尽管这还不是我们有史来最糟糕的情况。
That wouldn't even be that bad a day for us...historically speaking.
这个数据对吗？
Is that figure right?
不知道，我不确定。
I don't know, I can't, for sure.
埃里克・戴尔呢？- 我们把他的手机停了。
Where is Eric Dale? - We shut his phone off.
然后我给他老婆打了电话，她说他不在家。
So, I called his wife. Who says,  he's not home.
他个小样蹲哪儿酒吧哭呢吧…
He's probably crying in a fucking beer somewhere.
发现这个事儿的小子呢？
Where's the kid who did this?
我派他们出去找埃里克了。
I sent him out looking for Eric.
他知道自己在干什么吗？把他弄回来！
Do you think he knows what he's doing? Get him back.
这些妞一晚上挣多少钱？1500美元？
What do you think these girls make a night? 15 hundred?
2000美元？差不多。
2 grand? 2 grand. Fuck.
的确，能赚啊。
That's.. that's pretty great.
综合考虑经济效益的话。
I mean, you know, all considered.
我们在酒吧。没找到他。到处问了，没人看到他。
Will? Yep. no. We asked, no body sees him.
好吧，就回来。
Okay, Yeah.
好吧，那你说罗杰斯一年挣多少钱？
Alright, so come on,What you think Rogers makes in a year?
我不知道…
I have no idea
猜一个，消遣嘛。
Come on, play along.
75万？
Three quarters of a million?
别逗了。
Come on.
根本没沾边儿。
That was not even close.
要多得多。
Much more.
100万？
A million?
威尔・艾默生去年都挣了250万.
Will Emerson made two and half million last year.
-可恶！-这算啥！
-Fuck you! -Fuck me?
你怎么知道的？
How do you know that?
他告诉我的，我问他了。
He told me.  Well I asked him.
-靠谱儿吗？-差不多吧。
-Do you think that's true? -Yeah probably.
-真可恶… -为毛啊？
-That's fucked up. -Why, why's that fucked up?
-你觉得这正常吗？-正常…啥是正常？
-Does that seem right to you? -Right?
上帝啊。
Jesus.
所以你想想罗杰斯挣了多少？
So, what do you think that means Rogers puts away?
我不知道，塞斯。我就知道堵车真烦。
I have no idea, Seth. This traffic's a fucking nightmare.
伙计们？
Gentlemen?
罗杰斯先生。
Well, Mr. Rogers..
和我们一起来吧。
Come with us, please.
山姆，这是我说的塞斯・布雷格曼和皮特・沙利文。
Sam this is Seth Bregman and this is Peter Sullivan.
我们这是去哪儿？
Will... Where are we going?
我们去看看别人对你所做的工作有什么意见。
Going to get a second opinion on your work Peter.
山姆你有什么要给我们看的？
So Sam what do you have for us?
等会儿就来，这个点儿
Well... they'll be here in a minute. Finding someone
找人在影印室干活还真是不容易。
in the copy room at this hour was a little bit of a challenge.
好吧我们直接开始介绍。
Okay, let's go right into introduction.
这是莎拉・罗伯特森，首席风险评估分析师。
This is Sarah Robertson who you know, chief risk assessment officer..
拉米什・沙，楼上办公室的，大卫公司的内部咨询师。
Ramesh Shah from upstairs and David Horn one of the firm's in house council.
很高兴见面，这是我的交易负责人，威尔・艾默生。
Nice to meet you all. This is my head of trading, Will Emerson.
皮特・沙利文和塞斯・布雷格曼，都是风险部的。
Peter Sullivan, and Seth Bregman. They work in our risk department.
埃里克・戴尔呢？
Where is Eric Dale?
他在今天被解雇了。
He was let go today.
那你们风险部还剩下谁？
Who's left in your risk department?
今天就只有皮特
As of today that would be Peter
和初级分析师塞斯。
and our junior analyst Seth.
威尔・艾默生？- 我的。发给大家吧。
Will Emerson? - Yes. Please just hand it out.
显然埃里克已经分析了一段时间了，
Apparently Eric had been working on this for some time
但是没能完成。
but wasn't able to finish it,
今天早上他离开公司的时候
This morning, as he left the building;
他把这件事交给皮特让他看看。
He handed the program to Peter here, and asked him to take a look at it.
皮特就看了。
Peter did.
他把埃里克忽略的几件事做完了。
He put in a few things out that Eric seemed to be missing..
你们手里的就是结论。
and this is what came out.
皮特这是你做的？
Peter, Is this your work?
大部分是戴尔先生的工作……
Mostly Mr. Dale's...
但是这是你的手稿？
But is this your draft?
对。
Yes.
是在戴尔的计算基础上展开的，不过是我做的。
Again, expanded on original work of Eric's. But yes.
- 你是什么背景？- 我的背景？
- What is your background? - My background?
你的简历。
Your CV.
我在公司一直和埃里克一起工作，已经两年半了…
I've been with the firm for 2 and half years working with Eric that whole time...
但是我还有麻省理工的工程师
But I hold a doctorate in engineering, speciality
和推动力学专业的博士学位。
in propulsion, from MIT, with a Bachelors from Penn.
推动力学专业是什么？
What's a specialty in propulsion, exactly?
我的论文是关于固定配比
My thesis was a study in the way that friction ratios
现有数据对重力流失方面的研究。
effect steering outcomes in aeronautical use under reduced gravity loads.
- 所以你是个火箭科学家？- 曾经是。
-So, you are a rocket scientist?   - I was.
有意思，那你怎么又来了这？
Interesting. How did you end up here?
反正都是数字么，只是改变一下
Well it's all just numbers really, you're just changing
计算的方式… 而且坦白地说，
what you're adding up... and if I may speak freely;
这里的收入相对更吸引我。
the money here is, considerably more attractive.
现在几点了？
What time is it?
2：15。
It's 2:15.
我想你们两位还没
And I'm guessing, by the fact that you two
提到有任何计算复核过？
haven't said anything that the math checks out?
我们需要时间分析下这个，
Look, we'd need some time to go over this,
但沙利文看上去很有把握。
but Mr. Sullivan here seems to know what he's doing.
所以看来我们的确有麻烦了。
So, it would appear we have a problem.
- 几点了？ - 2：16。
- What time is it? - 2:16.
完蛋。
Fuck me.
糟糕。
山姆…
Sam..
把这事儿从我们的帐目上摆平，
How long under normal operations,
你的人一般需要多长时间？
would it take your people to clear that from our books?
什么？
What?
- 所有的？- 没错。
- All of it? - Yes.
我不知道，几周吧。
I don't know, weeks.
- 几周？- 没错，几周。
- Weeks? - Yeah, weeks.
但你很清楚我们的生意是要买和卖。
But as you certainly know our business is selling AND buying.
没有任何一方都做不成。
Doesn't work for very long without both components.
如果我们现在停止买入一两天，
We suddenly stops buying for a day or two;
这可不是什么能藏得住的事，
that's not something you can ust doesn't hide under the rug, it gets out
一旦传出去… 很快
and when it does... this whole thing
我们就玩儿完了。
comes to a end... and right quick.
- 我明白了。- 真的？
- I understand. - Do you?
真的。
Yes.
你们的楼层上还剩下多少交易员？
How many traders do we have left between your floor and Petersen's?
我不知道，应该是…60个？ - 对，60个。
I don't know, what? Sixty? - sixty.
我们再仔细看看这个，
Jared as I looke at this more closely,
毕竟这是用估计亏损风险数值算出来的。
it's these VAR numbers that are really setting this thing off.
就像我刚才说的，直说的话，
As I was saying.. just speaking completely off the record.
用不了多久就会有人发现我们的这些问题。
It's only a matter of time before someone else startsputting these in.
他们也会算出同样的结果。
and they come up with exactly the same results.
就是我们现在看的这份。
And look at exactly what we're looking at right now;
假设他们还没看过。
If they haven't already.
明白。
Understood.
萨拉，允许放在账面上的资产价值是多少？
And Sarah, what value would you allow to be placed on those assets
如果必须放的话？
that might be left on the books, if they had to?
为什么还在账面上？
Why would they still be on the books?
因为显然没有人愿意去买这些傻玩意儿了。
Because suddenly nobody wants to fucking buy them.
山姆！你丫安静会儿行吗？
Fuck you Sam! Will you give me a fucking break here?
没有市场的话，这要花上几周甚至几个月
Without an active market, it'd take weeks or months
的时间我才能算出精确的数字。
for me to come up with accurate value on them.
我要一块一块的算。
You'd have to go block by block.
杰拉德，这是个简单的问题好么，
Yeah. Look, Jared, it's a very simple business,
我们讨论过这问题的。-喂！
right? We talked about this question once. -Sam!
威尔，皮特，还有那谁，
Will, Peter, and what the fuck is his name?
塞斯，你们先出去一下好吗？对了，
Seth, Could you please, give us for a few moments. And Peter?
- 还有人知道这个吗？- 除了我们没别人了。
- Has anyone else has seen this? - No one aside from us.
- 还有埃里克・戴尔？- 对。
- And Eric Dale? - Yes.
而且我们还不知道埃里克・戴尔在哪儿？
And can it really be possible that we don't know, where Eric Dale is?
我给他老婆打电话了，他还没回家…
I called his wife. He hasn't come home yet ...
而且我们还把他的手机停了。
and we turned off his phone today.
完胜了。我想知道他去哪儿了。
Perfect. Well, I'd like to know where he is.
我了个娘，那家伙是谁啊？
Jesus fucking Christ! Who is that guy?
- 山姆的上司。- 老成的好像有50岁了。
- He's Sam's boss. - He looks like he's fifteen years old.
- 他才40。 - 怎么会有这种事儿？
- He's Forty. - Yeah, How does that happen?
这种事儿一直都有。
Oh it happens all the time.
就我碰不上。他们都是魔鬼。
Except to me. He's a fucking killer.
他们在里面会谈些什么呢？
What are they talking about, in there?
不好喽。
It ain't pretty.
什么不好了？
What ain't pretty?
假如没人买我们的理财产品的后果…
If people suddenly stop buying what we're selling....
杰瑞，你不能想做什么就做什么。
Jared, you cannot be doing what you are thinking about doing?
我没什么别的选择。
Well, I don't see any other choice.
什么意思？你怎么没的选？
What does that mean? Fuck you... you don't have a choice.
我有吗？山姆你到底有没有看过这些数字？
Fuck me? Did you even looked at the numbers Sam?
当然，我看过。
Yes, but what do I know.
沙，如果我说错了纠正我一下。
Correct me, if i'm wrong, Mr.Shah.
但是这些资产和负债不再平衡
But..These number, they don't add up.
账面市值已经只是空壳了。
One and one, no longer makes Two.
如果可以的话，我还需要一些时间…
If I may, I'd like a little more time.
我们之前就谈过这个。
We have talked about this.
我们需要点时间才能给你结果。
We need a little time before to give you our conclusion.
好吧，我们45分钟之后见。
We meet again in 45 minutes.
山姆，你有原始数据吗？
Sam, do you have the file?
你要怎么办？
What are you going to do?
给他打电话？
Are you going to call him?
我已经打了。
I already have.
上帝啊。
Jesus.
哇，太漂亮了。
Wow. It's gorgeous.
掉下去也要很久。
It's a long way down.
是啊。
Yes, it is.
我靠，别这样。
Don't do that, C'mon.
知道么有人站在这个边缘要掉下去的时候
Did you know the fear most people experience when they
害怕的不是他们会掉下去。
stand on the edge like this isn't the fear of falling.
而是怕他们会自己跳下去。
It's the fear that they might jump?
这太深奥了，你不能别这么压抑么…
Well, that's very deep and depressing, thank you.
有时候我心里是有点阴暗。
Yeah, well...I'm a little dark.. Sometimes.
下来吧，威尔，下来吧。
Come down, please. C'mon...Will?
好吧，去他的。
Yeah, Fuck it!
今天不见上帝了。
Not today.
看来他们要把这些破玩意儿全甩卖了。
So it looks like, they are gonna make us dump this shit.
什么？
What?
等着瞧吧。
You watch.
怎么甩？
How?
- 你会知道的。- 他们能怎么卖？
- You'll see! - How could they do that?
不可能完成的任务。但他们总会有办法的。
You can't...it's impossible. But they'll figure out a way.
我在这地方10年了，我见过的事情你们都…
I've been at this place for ten years and I've seen some things you wouldn't..
你们根本都不会相信。
you wouldn't believe...
这些都搞定的时候，他们可以毫发无损。
when all is said and done... they do not lose money.
即使其他所有人都在赔钱，
They don't mind if everyone else does,
但他们不会。
but they don't loose.
威尔？
Will?
你去年真的挣了250万？
Did you really make two and half million last year?
嗯，对。
Yeah..sure.
你怎么花的这钱？
How did you spend it all?
很快就空了。
They expire quickly.
你知道的，口袋里是藏不住钱的。
You know, You'll learn and spend what's in your pocket.
250万美元很快就花完了？
Two and half millions goes quickly?
对，我们算算看。
Alright, let's see.
税收拿走了一半，只给我剩了125万。
The tax man takes half up front. So, you're left with one and a quarter.
房贷又花了30万。
My morgage takes another 300 grand.
我又给我爸妈15万让他们花。
I send 150 home for my parents, you know..to keep them going.
- 剩多少了？ - 80万。
- So, what's left? - Eight hundred.
15万买车，
I spend 150 on a car.
7万5花在饭店里，
About 75 in restaurants,
大概，5万买衣服，
Probably, 50 on clothes.
又存了40万以防万一。
And I put 400 away for a rainy day...
明智。
That's smart.
嗯，看起来金融风暴就要来了。
Yeah, as it turns out. It looks like the storm's coming.
还有12万5呢？
You still got 125.
我花了76，520美元找小姐
Yeah, I did spent 76,520 dollars on Hookers,
和看脱衣舞上。但主要是找小姐。
booze and dancers. But mainly, hookers.
七万六千五？
76,5..?
一开始我也很震惊，但后来我意识到
Yeah, It was a little shock initially, but then
我可以以娱乐开销的名义报销一大部分。
I realise that I could claim most of it off, as entertainment.
你多大了？
How old are you?
43。
43.
真是怪了。
This is bizzare.
这就像个梦。
It's like a...dream.
我也不知道，好像如梦初醒。
Oh, I don't know, seems like we actually may have just woken up.
请进。
Come in.
怎么样？
How do we look?
我该走了。
I should go.
不，你留下来。
No, you should stay.
怎样？
So?
没有错…
It's legit...
那孩子是对的。
the kid killed it.
这个公式没用了。
The formula is worthless.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
公式失效了。
It's broken.
全世界有8兆美元的钱
There are eight trillion dollars of paper
都指着这个公式呢。
around the world relying on that equation
但是我们错了。
We were wrong.
不，你的意思是… 你错了。
No, You mean..you were wrong.
别惹我说出来…
Don't get me started....
我们谈过的！
We discussed this!
我去会议室了。
I'm heading to the conference room.
不，你得听听。
No, I want you to hear this.
我不想听。
I don't want to hear this.
你觉得我凭什么在这干了这么多年？
How do you think I've stuck around this place so long?
我给图尔德打电话了。
I've called Tuld.
我们有备用方案吗？
Is there a contingency plan here?
备用方案？
A contingency plan?
- 对。- 没有，我们把所有钱都押在这里了。
- Yes. - No, We went all in on this one.
那我们现在彻底暴露了，是么？
So, we've got ourselves quite exposed here... haven't we?
对图尔德还是对市场？
To Tuld or the market?
都是。
To both.
他来了？
He's here?
图尔德的直升机到了。
Tuld's helicopter just landed.
我知道，一起来吧。
I know, come with us.
- 山姆呢？- 我不知道，我们几个都去？ -是的。
- Where's Sam? - I don't know, You sure..you want all of us? -Yes.
进去之前给大家一点建议。
Just one piece of advice for everyone before we go in there.
一会场面会不太好看，
This could get a little ugly.
但不管怎么样… 实话实说就好了。
but whatever you do... just... tell the truth.
别净捡好听的，刚才怎么说一会儿还怎么说。
No sugar coating. Do not change a word of it.
谁都别自作聪明。
no one here is smart enough...
火箭科学家也是。
Including the rocket scientist.
这边。
This way please.
他已经在里面等你了。
He's already in there waiting for you.
很好。
Excellent!
大家坐吧。
Please sit down.
欢迎大家。
Welcome everyone.
很抱歉在这么晚了叫大家过来，
I must apologize for dragging you all here at such an uncommon hour;
但据我所知，有些事情要马上处理！
but from what I've been told, this matter needs to be handled urgently!
事实上，我们几周前就应该处理了。
so urgently, in fact.. it probably should have been addressed weeks ago...
但现在木已成舟了。
but that is spilled milk...Under the bridge!
那么，谁和我说说到底发生了什么？
So, why doesn't somebody tell me what they think is going on here?
图尔德先生，就像我之前说的，
Well, Mr. Tuld.. as I mentioned earlier..
如果你把第13页最上面的数字和…
if you compare the figure at the top page 13...
杰瑞，你就打开天窗亮着说吧。
Jared, it's a ..just speak to me in plain english.
我要听那个把这个算出来的人说… 沙利文，对吗？
But I'd  like to speak to the guy who put this together... Mr. Sullivan is it?
他能直接说明白吧？
Does he speak English?
什么？
Sir?
我要和那个算出这堆问题的分析师说话。
I'd like to speak to the analyst who seems to have stumbled across this mess.
好的，是皮特・沙利文，就在那。
Certainly, that would be Peter Sullivan. Right here.
哦，沙利文亲，早上好。
Oh Mr.Sullivan. You are here! Good morning.
也许你能告诉我这里发生了什么。
And maybe, you could tell me.. what you think is going on here.
而且请你把我当作孩子一样，解释清楚，
And please speak as you might to a young child ..
甚至当作金毛猎犬。
or a golden retriever.
这么说吧，我能坐到这个位置上不是因为我的智力。
It wasn't brains, that got me here. I can assure you of that.
好吧，也许您知道我在这和罗杰斯先生一起工作。
Well, sir. As you may or may not know I work for Mr.Rogers.
是一位风险评估管理分析师。
As an associate in the risk assessment and management office at GSMBS
放松点，站起来说，大点声。
Just relax, stand up. Tell us in clear voice.
告诉大家问题的性质。
What is the nature of the problem.
好的… 您也许知道，
Yes... Well as you probably know over
在过去的36到40个月里，
the last 36-40 months the firm has begun
公司在包装新的按揭证券理财产品，
packaging new MBS products;
它是包含交易国债等
that combine several different traunches of rating
好几块的产品组合。
classification in one tradable security.
该产品带来了很大账面收益，我想您已经留意到了。
This has been enourmously profitable... as I imagine you noticed.
必须的。
I have.
现在公司的这个产品每天都能卖出很多。
Well the firm is currently doing a considerable amount of this business every day.
我们今天在这的主要问题是…
The problem..which is I guess why we are here tonight.
我们… 公司花了大概一个月的时间…
is that it takes us... the firm, about a month...
才能理清该产品的实际效益。
to layer these products correctly.
从风险控制管理的角度上来说，这很危险。
thereby posing a challenge from a risk assessment standpoint.
不好意思，有什么问题？
And Mr. Sullivan that challenge is?
我们要花上比想象多得多的时间来做效益分析。
We have to hold these assets on our books longer than we might ideally like to.
好吧。
Yes.
但问题是，这些产品从本质上说，
But the key factor is here is, these are essentially
只是抵押债款，所以允许我们大幅提高警戒杠杆，
just mortgages, that has allowed us to push the leverage considerably..
这样就使潜在风险被忽视--谁都不想的，
beyond what you might be willing or allowed to do;
在任何其它情况下，风险会一再爆表，
in any other circumstance, thereby pushing the risk
但是却不会触发任何预警。
profile without raising any red flags.
好，谢谢，请坐。我猜你这说的是，
Now, Thank you...sit down. What I am guessing, your report here says;
让我理下思路，
give me some rope,
我想你的意思是…
what I am guessing, it says is that..
就是说，考虑到
considering the, shall we say?
过去一两周我们都在悬崖边上行走
bumpy road, we've been on the last week or so.
但你和你身边很多同事辛苦工作了这么久，到头来…
But the figures your brilliant co- workers up the line ahead of you had come up with..
这些指数报废了。
don't make much sense anymore;
所以才有了今天这一出
Considering what's taking place today?
实际上不是今天才发生的，
Actually not taking place today...
这个情况两周前就开始了。
but what's already taken place over the last two weeks.
那么你是说，这早就发生了？
So, you are saying , this had already happened?
是吧。
Sort of.
沙利文，你的计算模型对在座各位意味着什么？
And Mr. Sullivan, what does your model say that that means...for us here?
这次是危机的井喷。
Well, that's where it becomes a projection.
但是… 呃…
But... ummm..
和我说话别左顾右盼，亲。
You're speaking with me Mr. Sullivan.
好吧…
Well... sir...
如果我们账面上的这些资产下跌25%的话，
If those assets decrease..by just 25 percent, and remain on our books...
那损失…
that loss...
比我们整个公司现在的市值还要多。
would be greater than the current market capitalization of this entire company.
你的意思…
So what you're telling me...
就是说…
is that...
这和旋要停止了。
music is about to stop.
而我们手里攒下了整个资产阶级烂摊子的
and we are going to be left holding... 'the biggest bag of odorous excrement'
最大包垃圾?
ever assembled in the history of capitalism?
呃先生，我可能…
Well sir, I'm not sure I'd..
不会这样形容这件事，但是用你的话来说，
put it that way, but let me clarify...using your analogy,
这个模型显示…
what this model shows...
你说的和旋，开始变得拖沓了，
is the music, so to speak, just slowing,
你说的停止的情况，
If the music were to stop, as you put it,
与这个模型的结论并不接近，
then this model would not be even close;
其实这比停止了要糟糕得多。
to that scenario. It would be considerably worse.
我告诉你吧，沙利文先生。
Let me tell you something Mr. Sullivan.
你想没想过为什么我会坐在这个位子上？
Do you care to know, why I'm in this chair with you all?
为什么我是你们的老板？
Why I earn the big bucks?
想过。
Yes.
我坐上这个位置只有一个原因，
I'm here for one reason
仅仅一个原因。
and one reason alone.
我在这里是去猜测，那乐音一周、一个月、
I'm here to guess, what the music might do, a week, a month,
甚至一年之后的样子。
a year from now.
这就是原因！
That's it!
没别的了。
nothing more...
我今天晚上站在这…
I'm standing here tonight...
我觉得 什・么・声・音・都・没・听・到…
I'm afraid that, I don't hear... a... thing...
万籁俱寂。
just... silence!
现在你知道了，音乐停止了。我们要怎么办？
So, now that we know that the music has stopped, what can we do about it?
科恩? 罗伯特森?
Mr. Cohen, Ms. Robertson,
我想这是你们该表现的时候了。
I'm afraid, I think..this is where you are supposed to step back in.
我们今晚一直都在依赖沙利文先生。
Lord knows we've relied enough on Mr. Sullivan tonight.
你们有什么信息？
What have you got for us?
你们第一天进我办公室的时候
What have I told you since...
我对你们说了什么？
the first day you stepped into my office?
这个行业里有三种谋生技巧：
There are three ways to make a living in this business...
拼业绩，拼头脑，拼作弊。
Be first, be smarter, or cheat.
我不作弊。
Now, I don't cheat...
尽管我认为我们这里有很多聪明人，
And although I like to think, we've some pretty smart people in this building.
一心搞好业绩会简单的多。
it sure is a hell of a lot easier to just be first.
今天把这些卖光。
Sell it all...today!
能做到么，山姆？
Is that even possible Sam?
可以，但是代价呢？
Yes, but at what cost?
我愿意付啊。
I'll have to pay.
真的么？
Really?
我这么觉得。
I think so.
这次震荡会怎么影响到我们？
Where does this gonna come back to us?
各种方式。
Everywhere.
山姆，我觉得你好像没听懂你的下属刚才说的话…
Sam, I don't think you seem to understand what your boy here had just said...
如果我要你这么做，
if I made you...
你会怎么处理？
how would you do it?
让交易员在早上6点半开例会，
Well, you call the traders in for their normal 6:30 meeting...
老实跟他们说明情况。
and you be honest with them.
反正他们很快都会知道。
B'cos they're gonna know it's the end either way.
所以你要给他们一份奖励，很多的奖金。
so you'd have to throw them a bone, and a pretty big one.
所以大家要赶紧跳出风暴之门…
And then, you've gotta come out of the gate storming...
不要掉期交易，什么都不要。
No swaps..no nothing.
10：15之前干掉40%，11点前要卖完。因为到午餐的时候，
40 percent done by 10:15; by 11 O'clock all your trades have to be gone. 'cos by lunch-time
丑闻就会满天飞。
words are gonna be out.
到下午2点还能以65%的成本价卖出已经是算你走运了。
and by two o'clock you'll be getting 65 cents on the dollar, if you're lucky,
联邦调查局的人马上就会过来找你麻烦。
and the feds will be in here up your ass trying to slow you down.
- 拉米什？ - 他们会让你慢下来…
- Ramesh? - They can slow you down...
但不能阻止你，卖的是你的资产。
but they can't stop you. it's yours to sell.
约翰… 就算…
John...even if..
我们能顺利走到这一步… 可不是说说就能办到...
we manage pull that off, and that's saying something...
但真正的问题是…
The real question is...
我们要卖给谁呢？
Who are we selling this to?
过去两年里的那些买家，以及其他任何愿意买的人。
The same people we've been selling to for the last two years, and whoever else will buy it.
但是，如果你这么做了
But John, If you do this.
你会让市场瘫痪好几年，那就崩了。
You would've killed that market for years. It's over.
而且你知道你卖的东西毫无价值。
And you are selling something that you know has no value.
我们以市场的价格
We are selling to willing buyers
卖给愿意购买的买家
at a current fair market price,
这样我们才能幸存！
so that WE may survive!
但以后你再也不能向那些人卖出任何东西了。
You'll never sell anything to any of those people ever again.
- 我明白。- 真的么？
- I understand. - Do you?
你才不明白
Do You???
就这么定了！
This is it!
我告诉你，就这么定了！
I'm telling you. This is it.
现在是… 4点钟。
It's 4:00...O'clock.
杰瑞你在5点之前给我个方案。
Jared you've got till 5:00 to break this down and draw me up a plan.
除了这的人还有谁知道这件事的，哪怕一星半点？
Is there anyone else who knows what's in there right now, block by block?
埃里克・戴尔。
Eric Dale.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
他今天已经被公司解雇了。
As of today he is no longer with the firm.
我们一直在找他。
We have been trying to locate him.
- 卡梅隆？ - 在。- 六点之前把戴尔弄回来。
- Carmelo? - Yes? - Get me Eric Dale here by Six.
知道了。
Done.
我们一小时之后再回来开会。
We meet back here in an hour.
山姆，我们谈谈。
Sam, let's talk.
好大一座城市。
This is a hell of a town.
我一直都很喜欢这地方。
I've always loved this place.
从到这儿的第一天开始，喜欢这里的一切。
Since the day i arived. Everything about it.
山姆，这事上你会站在我这边么？
Sam, are you gonna go with me on this?
我不知道，约翰。
I don't know John.
这事儿太糟糕了。
This one is very ugly.
曾经咱们都是销售人员。
You and I were salesmen.
我们卖东西，这就这样，一点都不复杂。
We sell. That's what we do. It's not complicated.
没错。
Exactly.
因此你应该很清楚
And you know damn well..
只有保证一笔交易有所回报，今后才有持续的客源。
you don't make a sale unless you think the guy is gonna come back for more,
我们有过教训。但明天我们就声名尽毁了。
That's the lesson we learned. and tomorrow we are done.
可这事已经定了。
But this is it, Sam.
又是这句。你这是什么意思？
You keep saying that. What's that supposed to mean?
这次麻烦太大。
This is the big one.
我们中的大部分人都逃不出这场灾难。
Most of us aren't gonna make it out of this one.
- 我们？ - 整个华尔街。
- Us?  - The street.
你什么意思？
What are you talking about?
我要面对的局面不是这周就能结束的。
This isn't  the last situation I will have to deal with this week.
这还只是个开始。
This is just the start.
那是因为你开始了这一切。
It's the start because you are starting it.
也许吧。我不信就这么完了。
Maybe. But I don't believe that.
我不要完蛋。
Not this time.
那些账面盈亏完全无法平衡。
The numbers just don't add up anymore.
我同意你这个观点。这话我说了多少年了。
Well I agree with you there. I've been saying that for years.
如果那孩子算出来的这结果是对的…
I mean if this kid out there can come up with this thing...?
我没办法明知道结果还要去害其他人。
I don't think I can go in knowing what I know and put the hammer down on these guys.
山姆你什么时候变得这么慈悲了？
When did you start becoming so soft, Sam?
少来冷嘲热讽，是你自乱阵脚。
Fuck you soft, you're panicking.
如果你走出这第一步，
If you're the first one out the door;
没人会说我乱了阵脚。
That's not called panicking.
显然你运营的消息比我多得多。
Well, you are obviously operating with more information than i have.
但我想你这次会毁了这公司的。
But I think this could destroy this firm.
没人会再相信你了。
No one will ever trust you again.
你在知情的情况下毁了他人的事业。彻底的。
Knowingly putting people out of business. Full stop.
我能应付的，山姆。
Let me deal with that, Sam.
怎么样？
How'd that go?
一场闹剧。
This is a fucking shit show.
- 他们真打算这么干了？- 很可能。
- They are gonna go with it? - Probably.
疯了！
Jesus!
记住今天吧，孩子们
Remember this day boys,
记着今天。
Remember this day.
现在采取什么策略？
What's the strategy here?
这正是我要下楼和他们一起研究的事情。
Well, that's why i'm headed downstairs, to work it with my guys.
你、我和约翰来研究。
No, no, you and I... With John.
我们不需要开小会，萨拉，这不是我的处理方式。
I'm not sure that we need one, Sarah. That's not the way I do things.
求你别这样
Please.
图尔德知道我们还没找到对策，
Listen, He knows where we are still on this.
一直都知道。
All along.
那正是我想说的。
That's exactly my point.
就算我们商讨过…
And knowing what was discussed..
你也得不到任何保证。
by both you and I. I don't think this could provide you with anything.
除非你有这方面的错觉。
other than, false sense of comfort.
我不是在寻求保障安慰。
I'm not looking for sense of comfort here, Sarah.
估计也求不到。
I don't think there's one to be found.
我再问一遍，现在的对策？
So again, what's the strategy?
除了卖空我们什么也做不了。
I'm just not sure there's much more to do in this.
这事已经很清楚了，
It's very simple.
别想瞒着我。
Don't even think of fucking me on this.
因为如果公司要倒闭了，
because if we are going down...
你知道大家会一起完蛋。
you damn well know we'll  be together.
不，我不这么觉得。
No, I'm not sure I do know that.
你觉得图尔德去年挣了多少钱？
What do you think Tuld made last year?
你丫能闭嘴么？
Would you shut the fuck up.
8千6百万。
86 mil.
光是工资和分红。
In bonuses and salary .
真的？
Really?
当然，有公开记录的。
Sure, it's public record.
真有钱。
That's a lot of fucking money.
他曾有十多亿美元。
He was worth a billion.
曾经？
Was?
今天以后就不是了。
Until today.
-是么 -走着瞧
-Really? -We'll see.
-我去煮点咖啡。你们还要点什么吗？-我的够了。
-I'm gonna get some coffee. Someone need anything else? -I'm all right.
我需要点新鲜空气。
I could use some real air.
好主意。
Probably a good idea.
-你觉得行么 -你指什么行不行
-Is it all right, Will? -What do you mean, all right?
我一个人出去一会
Take it out, for a minute?
怎么不行，你又不是囚犯
Yes, of course, you're not a prisoner.
你要我跟你手拉手散步么
You want me to hold your hand?
你为什么要放那么多水果啊！
Why did you put all this fruit on that?
您好，我是威尔。
Hello, Will Emerson.
喂？
Hello?
不用了谢谢，我知道了。
No, thank you. I understand.
我们会谨慎处理。
No, we'll be discreet.
谢您了。
Thank you.
啥事
What?
埃里克老婆。
Eric's wife.
他没事 在家呢 就是不想和我们说话
He's alive, he's home. He doesn't wanna speak to us.
也不知道他老婆给我打电话。
He doesn't know she rang me.
他住哪儿？
Where's he live?
住海兹。
The heights.
要通知图尔德手下那个卡梅隆么
Should I call Tuld's guy?
不，埃里克是自己人。迫不得已时
No.it's Eric...the last thing we need
才叫那些人去。你们俩去把他带回来。
is those guys going over there, you two go get him try to bring him.
但是记得要赶在6点之前。
But you've got to be back by 6:00 AM.
我讨厌布鲁克林。
I hate Brooklyn.
我能进来么？
May I come in?
进啊。坐吧。
Of course. Please, sit down.
嗯，我们决定要这么做了…
So... we are going to do this thing.
行啊。
Okay.
可能会很紧张。
It's going to be tight.
山姆和我们一道吗？
Is Sam on board?
还没有。
Not yet.
萨拉，
Sarah,
我需要一只替罪羊…
I need a head......
好对这层楼的交易员及所有股东有个交代。
to feed to the traders... on the floor and the board.
是我还是科恩？
Is it me or Cohen?
是你。
It's you.
可是你知道…
Of course you are...
我之前就提醒过你和科恩这件事。
well aware I filtered several warnings to you and Cohen about this .
一年前就说过。
A year ago.
我真心觉得现在不是说这个的时候。
I really don't think that's the best path for you to be taking at this point.
你会得到丰厚的补偿的。
you're going to be well taken care of.
显然这有点复杂。
Obviously it's quite complicated.
约翰，我了解这类规矩…
John I was told that in no uncertain terms...
这一直是个灰色地带。
It was always a very grey area.
一年以前我们就把这事
Actually it was made very clear at the time,
说的很清楚了。
by you me and Cohen.
希望你不要再跟我提这件事了。
I'd really appreciate it that you didn't fight me on this...
我们都把这事完全搞砸了
We all fucked this one up pretty good...
我要你呆在这里直到股市收盘。
We need you to stay here till this is finished and the markets close.
我明白。
I understand.
他们会在楼下和你核对那些数据，
They'll go over the numbers with you downstairs...
祝你好运。
Good luck.
尼马，杰瑞来了。
Oh fuck Jared... Jared's coming.
那家伙想干吗？
What's the boy wonder want?
有时间吗？
You got a minute?
- 我们要去接埃里克。- 我知道，就一会儿。
- We're just off to pick up Eric. - Yeah I know. Will only take a second.
好吧，怎么了？
Alright, what is it?
我和图尔德担心在这件事上,
Tuld and I have  concerns that Sam,
山姆可能无法作出正确的选择。
may not be willing to step up and do the right thing here.
这事儿以前没有过？
It's never been a problem?
没有。
No, it hasn't.
但像现在这样的敏感时期…
But, sometimes in an acute situation, Such as this...
对于究竟什么是对的
often what is right.
可能招致诸多猜疑。
Can take on, mutiple interpretations.
山姆知道该怎么做。
Sam will step up.
我知道他会的。
Oh, I know..he will.
但是如果他不肯，我是说如果…
But if he doesn't. IF he does not...
我们需要你准备好。
We need to know that, You will.
你们要知道我会怎么样？
You need to know that, I will... What?
你会和我们一道。
That you will step up.
我相信，山姆会做出正确的选择。
I have not doubt. That Sam will make the right decision.
但我想先说清楚，
But, just to make it clear.
他和我对什么是正确的事情，意见很一致。
He and I always have the same interpretation, Of what's right.
不管是不是什么敏感时期。
No matter, How acute... the situation.
( 肖邦 第15号前奏曲 )
天啊，这房子真不错。
Jesus, that's a nice place.
是啊。他刚买的。
Yeah,  it is.. he just bought it.
希望他用的是现金。
I hope it was with cash.
滚蛋，你个没良心哪壶不开提哪壶，
Fuck me. You are a heartless little shit sometimes.
不是用的现金。
and it wasn't.
别碰车上的按钮！
Don't touch any of the buttons!
你在干吗？
What are you doing here?
嘿
Hey?
皮特把你在算的模型算完了。
So..Peter finished that model you were working on.
真的？
Really?
麻烦大了。
Caused a shit storm.
我就知道。
I bet...it did.
你认为他算对了吗？
Do you think he's right?
他肯定是对的。
I know... he's right.
昨天晚上杰瑞・科恩和高级合作伙伴开了一个紧急会议。
Jared Cohen called an emergency meeting of the senior partners last night.
基于你的计算…
Based on your findings..
他们决定把我们所有产品全卖了。
They've decided to liquidate our entire position.
就今天！
Today!
我很抱歉。
I am very sorry about that.
他们担心你一个人在外面，要我把你带回去。
They are worried about you being out here. And  they want me to get you back.
- 搞什么  - 我建议...  - 去他的。
- Jesus! - I'm just saying.. - Fuck that.
- 好好考虑一下。- 得了，我签了字，离职了。
- Don't be rash. - Forget it, I've signed my papers. I'm out!
他们会补偿你的。
They will pay you.
我拿了辞退补偿了。
I've been paid enough, already.
你知道我造过桥么？
Did you know I built a bridge once?
什么？
Sorry?
造大桥。
A bridge.
没听说过啊。
No, I didn't know that.
我当时是个工程师。
I was an engineer by trade.
横跨俄亥俄州的多士巴 和西维吉尼亚州的玛瑟夫
It went from Dilles Bottom, Ohio to Moundsville West Virgina.
距俄亥俄河上方912英尺。
It spans 912 feet above the Ohio river.
每天有1.21万人通过这座桥。
12,100 people use this thing a day.
这为惠灵和新马顿赛
And It cut out 35 miles...
每边都省去了35英里的额外路程。
of extra driving each way, between Wheeling and New Martinsville.
加起来的话…
That's a combined...
每天为行人节省84.7万英里
847,000 miles of driving,a day...
等于每个月2.541千万英里
Worth 25,410,000 miles...a month;
即每年3.04亿英里
and 304 millions 920,000 miles a year.
省了
Saved.
我在1986年完成了那项工程，22年前了。
Now, I completed that project in 1986... that's 22 years ago.
这些年来，这座桥让人少走了60.70824亿英里冤枉路。
So, Over the life of that one bridge..that's 6 billion... 708 million...240 thousand miles...that haven't had to be driven!
时速算50英里好了。
At what? let's say... 50 miles an hour
那就是1.341648亿个小时。
So, that's a 134 million, 164 thousand 800 hours...
即 55.902万天。
or 559 thousand 20 days...
所以就那一座桥就省下了 当地两个社区的居民共1531年的时间
so that one little bridge has saved the people of those two communities a combined, 1531 years of their lives
而不用在车里浪费时间。
not wasted in a fucking car...
1531年！
One thousand five hundred and 31 years!
牛啊
Jesus.
我觉得… 你该回去了。
I guess... you better get back over there.
是啊
Yeah.
谢谢你能来。
Thanks for coming by.
乐意之至
You're welcome.
那是谁？
Who the fuck is this?
还用想，公司的人呗。
I'd imagine, it's the firm's people.
啊？
What?
图尔德不允许大意之举。
Tuld doesn't want any loose ends.
是他炒的我。
He fired me.
去他丫的。
Fuck 'em... Fuck 'em.
我同意，去他们的。所以先回公司
I totally agree...Fuck them. So, come back...
拿好你的钱，5点你就能回家了。
take the money, You'll be home by five.
否则的话，他们会把你的什么都吞了，红包、期货…
Otherwise, they are going to fight you on everything, they are going to fight you on the package, the options...
实际点
Be smart.
好吧，你比我强。
Well..You're a better man than I.
这句真相了。
That's always been true.
对，对对。
Yes, it has.
这房子不错。
The house looks good.
谢谢。
Thanks.
埃里克……
Hey Eric...
别老对自己这么苛刻好吗？
don't beat yourself up too much about this stuff, alright?
有的人就喜欢开半天车才能回到家。
Some people like driving the long way home.
谁他妈知道呢，对吧？
Who the fuck knows. Right?
啊，你在这。
There he is.
约翰。
John.
怎么样了？
How's it looking?
科恩做的不错，可以照他说的干。
Cohen has done a nice job. It can work.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
就是说，你知道的，
It means, as you very well know,
你是我们团队很重要的成员。
that you are a very important piece of this puzzle.
你真慷慨。
That's very generous.
这可不是白给的。
It's not a gift.
我要知道这件事上你和我同一战线。
I need to know you are with me on this.
我和公司同一战线。
I'm with the firm John.
除非你的人相信你，否则我从这些人那什么都得不到…
I won't get what I need out of your boys on the floor, unless they believe you...
他们得完全信任你才行。
unless they believe in you completely.
加入我的计划吧？
Are you in, on this?
我说过了我持保留意见。
I told you my reservations.
你不能有任何保留！
You can't have reservations!
我现在就要知道！
And I need to know now.
听着，约翰。我一直都是为公司考虑的。让我过去。
Look John..I'm  completely with the firm, as I always have been. Excuse me.
好吧，威尔，我会被炒吗？
Alright, Will. Am I getting fired?
我不知道。
I don't know.
好吧，基本上肯定会。
Yeah, almost definitely yes.
- 那你呢？- 我不会。
- Are you? - No.
塞斯，你没做错什么。只是你的天时地利不和。
Seth, its nothing you did. You're just in a wrong firm, in a wrong time.
年轻人总是被裁员的那个。
Young guys are always the one to get called.
我没什么好劝你的。
Listen, nothing i can say'll make you feel any better.
你会难受一阵子，过些日子就好了。
It's gonna suck for a while... and then you'll be fine.
你还好吧？
You alright?
嗯，我没事。
Yeah, yeah. I'm fine.
事情发展成这样，我也很抱歉。
For what its worth, I'm sorry this is happening to you.
不用，你没对不起我。
Don't be. You didn't do it to me.
总之，起码你走的时候会拿到一大笔钱。
Still, at least you're gonna have some nice cash to walk away with.
也许吧。
I guess.
- 这种事真的会影响到别人的。- 没错，像我这样的。
- This is really gonna effect people. - Yeah, it's gonna affect people like me.
不，我是说其他人。
No, real people.
拜托，塞斯。
Jesus, Seth.
如果你真的想在这个行当做下去，
If you really wanna do this with your life.
你必须相信你自己很重要。而且你的确是。
You have to believe you're necessary. And you are.
大家想要这样的生活，香车、
People wanna live like this. In their cars and
豪宅，可是他们根本都付不起。
their big fucking houses, that they can't even pay for.
这时候你就非常重要了。
Then, you're necessary.
他们能活得像个国王，唯一的理由是
The only reason, that they all get continue living like kings is
我们用手指把天平往他们那边压了一下。
'cos we got our fingers on the scales in their favour.
我要是把手拿开。
I take my hand off.
然后世界才是他妈的真正公平的，
Well then the whole world gets really fucking fair,
但是很快他们就会承受不住。
really fucking quickly and nobody asks you one shite.
他们其实并不想要真正的公平。
They say they do but they don't.
他们想要我们给他们更多的东西。
They want what we've to give them..
但同时又想假装无辜假装不知道这些东西怎么来的。
but they also wanna you know, play innocent and pretend they've no idea where it came from.
那就要我来为他们的这些行为埋单，尼玛的。
That's more hypocracy than I'm willing to swallow. So, fuck them.
都他妈滚蛋！
Fuck normal people!
你知道么，有趣的是，明天如果这事儿曝光了。
You know, the funny thing is. Tommorow, if all of these goes tits up.
他们会因为我们的“粗心”声讨我们。
They're gonna crucify us. For being, too reckless.
但我们不这么做呢?
But if we are wrong?
如果一切都真正公平了
And everything gets back on track.
这帮人会在笑掉大牙后，把自己搞得一团糟。
Well then, the same people are gonna laugh until they piss their pants.
到了那时候，我们就重新变回上帝派来的亲善大使。
Because, we are gonna look like the biggest pussies that God ever let through the door.
你觉得我们错了么？
Do you think we are gonna be wrong?
我不知道，别问我。
Nah, I don't know..fuck.
早上好。
Good morning.
皮特…
Peter...
来一根儿？
you want one?
我不抽烟。
I don't smoke.
好事，我也不怎么抽的。
That's good. I don't much either.
累吗？
Are you tired?
累什么？
Of what?
我又没像你那么拼命的工作。
Remember, I don't work as hard as you do.
不是吧。
Oh, That's not true.
其实是的。
No it is...actually.
- 我们今天会被解雇吗？- 也许吧。
- Are we all getting fired after today? - Probably.
他们会炒了你？
Are they going to fire you?
他们会换种说法。
Well, they won't exactly call it that.
算作怜悯的辞退吧。你不用陪我在这站着。
but... it'll be a mercy killing really. You don't have to stand out here for me.
我知道，我只是现在还不想回去。
No, I know. I really don't want to go back in there just yet.
我理解。
I understand that.
我认识你的儿子。
I think I know your son.
真的？
Really?
不是很熟…但是看起来是个好人。
Not well... but, he always seemed like a nice person.
他是个好人。
He is a nice person.
的确没有那么多缺点可说。
I guess you could say a lot worse about a guy.
他知道会发生什么吗？
Does he know what's about to happen?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你跟他说过吗？
Did you talk to him?
没有，我还没想到要跟他说。
No..I hadn't even thought of it.
他们飞过来了。
They're all coming in now.
是啊都来了。
Yes they are.
你以前做过这样的事吗？
Have you ever done anything like this?
没有，都比不了这次。
No... never.... not even close.
你确定我们只能这样…
Are you sure..it's the only...
或者说，这么做对吗？
or the... right thing to do?
对谁来说？
For who?
我不确定。
I'm not sure.
我也不知道。
Neither am I.
你没事吧？
You alright?
你要解雇我了。
You are about to fire me.
知道么，我只想在这里工作。
You know, this is.. This is all I've ever wanted to do.
真的？
Really?
他们都准备差不多了，你过几分钟就来吧。
It's almost ready for you, Ms Robertson. Couple of minutes.
你也被圈禁了？
You as well, huh?
对。
Yes.
没想到
Jesus!
抱歉。
Sorry.
谢谢。
Thank you.
我还以为他们没本事把你弄回来。
I didn't think they were going to be able to get you back here.
他们威胁要撤销我的所有权益，
They told me they were going to drag me through hell on everything
包括下两年的期货、医疗保险
the next two years.. my options, my healthcare
除非我回来，挣…
or I could come back here and make...
每个小时17.65万美元
$176,471.00 an hour
只要乖乖在这坐着。
to sit quietly...  in this room.
我好像没别的选择。
I couldn't see much of choice.
从来就没得选。
It never does.
回过头来看，
Obviously looking back,
之前我们没有及时地处理…
It was expressed with insufficient urgency...
但是你的观点是对的。
but your point was passed on...
我希望你理解。
I need you to know that.
埃里克。
Eric.
没事，我理解，相信我。
Its okay, I understand, believe me.
你本来也做不了什么。
there was nothing you could have done.
我觉得也是…
I guess...
那个时候…好像也没什么选择。
at the time... it didn't seem like there was much of a choice.
从来没有过。
It never does.
为了你的孩子?
Your kids, hah?
你的补偿奖金会有多少?
What is your package going to be like?
我不知道，我正等着呢。
I don't know, that's what I'm waiting for now.
可能很高哦。
It probably pretty good.
必须是。
It better be.
非常感谢大家能来这么早。
Thank you all for coming in a little early this morning,
昨天是很糟糕，我指望今天能跟大家说情况有所好转，
I know yesterday was pretty bad, and I wish I could say that today is going to be less so,
但其实并不是那样。
but that isn't going to be the case.
现在我应该给你们读这份通知，
Now, I am supposed to read this statement here to you all here,
但你们有空了自己看吧，我只想告诉你们这发生了什么。
but how bout you read it on your own time and I'll just tell you what the fuck's going on here.
我昨天整宿都在这。
I've been here all night.
和董事会的人开会讨论。
meeting with the executive committee.
最终决定卖出公司几个关键财产类的所有东西。
and the decision has been made to unwind a considerable portion of the firm's holdings in several key asset classes.
问题是，在公司看来，
The crux of it is... in the firm's thinking.
派对在今天早上结束了。
the party is over as of this morning.
在未来一段时间里，市场会有很大动荡。
There is going to be considerable turmoil in the markets for the foreseeable future.
他们觉得，这个动荡最好从我们这里开始。
And they believe... it is better, that this turmoil begin with us...
结果就是……
as a result...
公司决定卖出
the firm has decided to liquidate
大部分的固定收入的按揭证券
its majority positions of fixed income MBS..
今天一天。
today.
这是你们的信函，
These are your packets,
你们会看到你们今天的任务是什么。
you will see what accounts you are  responsible for today.
我想你们会很快
I'm sure it hasn't taken you long to..
明白这次买卖的意义，
understand the implications of this sale.
还会对你们与竞争对手间的关系，
on your relationships with your counter-parties
以及你们的事业，将产生的影响。
and as a result... on your careers.
我对董事会说出了
I have expressed this
真相
reality
他们也很理解这一点。
to the executive committee and they understand.
所以，
As a result,
如果你能卖出你手里93%的资产，
if you achieve a 93% sale of your assets...
你会得到140万美元的奖金。
you will receive a 1.4 million dollar one off bonus.
如果这层楼整体
If the floor as a whole
销售完成了93%，你们每人会另外获得130万美元的奖励。
achieves a 93% sale you will get an additional 1.3 million a piece.
如果你们没有经历过这样的事，
For those of you who have never been through this before,
那么我告诉你这就像是大甩卖的开始。
this is what the beginning of a fire sale looks like.
不用我告诉你头一个半小时有多么重要了。
I cannot begin to tell you how important first hour and half is gonna be.
我要你们找到每一个可以找到的买家。
I want you to hit every bite you can find.
商人、经纪人、顾客…
Dealers, brokers, clients...
你妈妈有意向也成。
Your mother, if she respond.
不要掉期交易，
No swaps.
我们今天只卖出。
It's outgoing only, today.
显然这不是我们所希望看到的，
Obviously, this isn't going  down the way that any of us would've hoped.
但是我们脚下的大地在颤抖了，
but the ground is shifting below our feet,
我们也没有别的选择。
And apparently, there is no other way out.
上帝啊，现在真的面临一个很特殊的局面…
Gods... this is Obviously, a very very unique situation...
如果我们今天成功了，
if we are successful today.
我们同时也会成功的砸了我们以后的饭碗。
We will have been successful in destroying our own jobs...
我不能向你们所有人都保证…
I can not promise that any of you.. all of you...
你们当中有一些人还是会被公司解雇。
Some of you would be repositioned within the firm.
但我会告诉你们，我为你们今天的工作相当骄傲。
but I can tell you that, I am very proud of the work we've done here today.
我在这家公司，
I have been at this place,
已经34年了，
34 years,
从我的经验来看，会有人为我们
I can tell you from experience, that people are going to
今天做的事情问候我们八辈儿祖宗。
say some very nasty things about what we do here today.
同时也会这样问候你们所效力的公司。
about what you've dedicated a portion of your lives to.
但说实话，总体来说，
But have faith that in the bigger picture,
我们展现了我们的能力，
our skills have not been wasted,
我们获得了许多成就，
we have accomplished much,
我们的天赋被用以
and our talents have been used...
成就更伟大的事业。
for the greater good.
这是你们的信函，加油干吧。
Here's your packets, get to work.
-西铁事务所，我是埃里克。-我找埃利奥特。
- City..this is Eric.      - Give me Elliott.
-西铁。-嘿，我是威尔・艾默生。
- City. - Hey, its Will Emerson.
-威廉啊，你怎么样？-我很好，最近干的怎么样？
- William, how are you? - I'm alright, how's the trouble at scribes?
总是输的一塌糊涂。
Busting my ass, as always.
你看，我试过劝你的。
You see, that's what i've been trying to tell you.
嘿，你知道我要跟你说啥吗？
John, why do you thing I'm saying this?
我知道你劝过。
I know you did.
你要我做什么？
What can i do for you?
我刚得到点儿消息，
Listen, I just got tapped on my shoulder,
我们有点项目要转移。
we've got some words over here that we need to move.
所以今天我的亏损就是你的收益。
So, today. It looks like my lost is your gain.
多大的盘子？
What kind of size you're talking about?
应该在你的屏幕上，我发给你了。
Should be on your screen, I just sent it.
- 天哪，什么价？- 96美元一股。
- Jesus, what is this gonna land? - 96 on a dollar.
- 91美元。- 你都拿走，94美元。
- 91? - Whole three and we're done at 94.
- 93.5美元？- 成交！
- 93 and a half? - Done!
- 交易所。- 嗨美女
- This is trading? - Hello, gorgious.
- 威尔，你们那怎么了？- 今天是转移交易日。
- Will, what's happening over there? - Today's moving day.
你们阴测测的要干什么？
What's the fuck are you guys so worked up about?
他们什么都没说，我只知道，
You think they tell me anything, all i know is that
今天我的亏损就是你的收益。你对我们很友好，
today my loss is your gain. Now, you're friendly
所以我就先找你来了。我这有2亿7千万
So, I'm coming to you first. I got two seventy mill
的担保基金，20年付清还有15年。
a fifteen year paying at a twenty half a part.
- 从哪来的？- 哪来的？谁在乎这个？
- Where is it from? - Where is it from? Do you care?
也不是…
No, not really. Now...
- 哪交易的？我听说你们… - 我现在只告诉了你这个事。
- Where's the trade? I'm hearing that you guys.... - I'm only sharing this with you right now!
- 85美元。- 成交。
- 85... - Done.
多维奇。
Deutsche.
威尔・艾默生。
It's Will Emerson.
- 操你妈，你这个骗子。- 不是吧，你还为那事儿生气呢？
- Fuck you, you lying bastard. - Come on, are you still angry about that.
甭说了，我挂了。
Word is out, i'm hanging up.
- 我麦罗。- 我劳伦斯。
- Merryll? - Lawrence.
你们在搞什么啊？
What the fuck are you guys doing over there?
- 就是一次春季扫货。- 我听说可不是这样的。
- Just a little spring cleaning. - That is not what i'm hearing.
好了劳伦斯，你是个买家吗？
Alright, Lawrence. Are you a buyer?
不一定，什么东西？
I'm not sure anymore. Where at?
怎么搞得，好像我在问你要卖什么货一样？
Why, it sounds like I should be asking you 'Where at.'
3.75亿的三年付清混合担保。- 哇塞…
375 mill at third year mixed.  - Fuck me..
你要不要？
Are you with me on this?
- 63美分一股。- 别扯了，我挂了。
- 63 cents? - or fuck you, I'm hanging up.
- 就63 - 我问一下，5分钟内告诉你。
- 63.  - Let me call my man, I'll come back to you in five.
或者65.5?
Maybe, sixty five and five.
好态度，别挂哦。
Well, alright then, stay on the line.
山姆，接电话。
Sam, pick up the phone.
山姆，接电话！
Sam...get on the line!
- 我刚联系了劳伦斯。- 什么情况？
- I got Lawrence in now. - Where are we?
-63美分。-哟，买什么？ -3.75亿的混合担保
- sixty three cent. - Jesus, and what? - 375 mill at mixed day.
给他65，卖了。
Get him to sixty five and hit it.
你在开什么玩笑啊？
Are you fucking kidding me on this?
这可是在一个交易上就损失了1亿美元。
That's a hundred million lost on a single trade.
我知道，卖了。
I understand...hit it.
好吧劳伦斯，65成交行么？
Well, Lawrence. We'd fill a kill at sixty five.
行诶。
It's filled.
干的不错。
Well done.
我想过来帮帮你，但他们现在就开始裁员了。
I just wanna give you heads up. They're gonna start sending a few people home now.
- 现在？- 对，很快就完。
- Now? - Yes, I know this ends.
-一向如此。-即使代价高昂，你们依然很棒。
- Of course.   - And for what it worth, you're still good.
真的。某位高层很欣赏你的表现。
Yeah. I guess someone upstairs really likes you.
山姆！请坐。
Sam!  Please sit.
真该好好恭喜你。
Congratulations are clearly in order.
我们尽力了。
We did the best we could.
你确实做了不少事情。
You did a hell of a job.
我很感激，坐吧。
And I thank you for that. C'mon sit.
不好意思我在吃东西，
Excuse me for eating, but...
今天真的很不容易。
It's been a long day.
- 你要点什么吗？- 不用了，谢谢。
- Can I get you something? - No, nothing, Thanks.
- 要我做什么？- 我要辞职。
- What can I do for you? - I want out.
我受够了，我要辞职。
I'm done, I want out.
- 这一天大家都不容易… - 我要你把我的期货全都兑现，
- It's a very difficult day for all... - I need you to release my options,
今天之后还值钱的话，我要我的分红，并且辞职。
If they're worth anything today, I want my bonus, I am out.
你可以保留你的分红，你的期货…
You'll get your bonus, your options...
但是蛋腚点儿。我要你再帮我干24个月。行么?
and keep a calm face. But i need you to stay with me for next 24 months..OK?
拜托了。笑一下成么。
Oh. come on, Sam. Put a smile on your face.
你今天做的很好，你自己也这么说。
You did some good today, you said that yourself.
知道吗
You know...
这之后我对整件事的感觉好多了。
I'm starting to feel a little better about all this whole thing.
山姆，你是世界上最幸运的人之一。
You're one of the luckiest guy in the world, Sam.
如果不是做这个你还在挖战壕呢。
You could've been digging dicks all these years.
那倒是。
That's true.
那样至少地上有几个坑证明我的工作。
And if I had, at least there's some holes on the ground to show for you.
我就不知道我们怎么把事搞得这么恶心？
I just don't know how the hell did we fuck this up, quite so much?
你什么时候开始良心发现了…真受不了。
When did you start feeling so sorry for yourself..its unbearable.
怎么，你觉得我们今天让一些人破产了。
So, you think we might've put a few people out of business today.
都是为了钱。
It's all for note.
你每天做这样的事情做了都快40年了。
But you've been doing that everyday, for almost 40 years Sam
这里一切，以及外头的所有都是为了钱。
If this is all for note, then so is everything out there.
只是货币。
Its just money.
都是虚构的。
It's made up.
纸币只是画着花纹的纸，所以我们不用
It's pieces of paper with a picture on it. So, we don't have to
为了它相互残杀，来点东西吃吧。
kill each other, just to get something to eat.
这没什么不对的。
Its not wrong.
现在和原来也没什么区别。
And it's certainly not different today, then it's ever been.
1637, 1797, 1819, 1937, 1957
1984,
金融危机那些年
1901, 1907... 1929, 1937..1974
还有1987年，那些混蛋差点整死我。
1987, Jesus! Didn't that fucker fuck me up good.
1992、1997、2000年，不管怎么取名。
92, 97..2000 and whatever we wanna call this.
都是同样的事，周而复始的。我们自身都难保。
All just for same thing, over and over..we can't help ourselves.
我们会想要，嗯… 控制它、或者阻止它或者减缓它的发展。
And we wanna like uh, control it, or stop it or even slow it.
可是我们从未能改变过丝毫。
We haven't even since slightly altered.
我们只能应对。
We just react.
我们做对了，就能赚到很多钱。
We get a lot of money,  if we get it right.
如果我们做错了，就会被这个行业抛弃。
And we get left by the side of road if we get it wrong.
一直如此，以后也不会改变，
And there has always been, and always will be..
赢家和输家的比例是不变的。
the same percentage of winners and losers
快乐的混蛋和悲伤的倒霉鬼，
happy fucks and sad sacks.
就像是肥猫和饿狗，比比皆是。
Fat cats and starving dogs, in this world.
今天过后可能我们这样的幸运者比之前多。
Yeah, then maybe more of us today, than there ever been...
但是输赢的比例，
but the percentages,
和原来一模一样。
they stay exactly the same.
好吧我会继续干，但不是因为你的迷你演说，
I'll do it John, not but because of the little speech,
而是我的确需要钱。
But because I need the money.
难以置信，这么多年下来，我还是不得不为钱折腰。
Hard to believe, after all this years.. But I... need the money.
你要留着那小子吗？
Are you gonna keep the kid?
留着？他会被升职的。
Keep him? He's gonna promote him.
现在是全体总动员了。
It's all hands on deck now Sam.
这事儿之后，我们还会有很多钱可捞，
There's gonna be a lot of money to be made, coming out of this mess.
我们需要挖出每个能用的人来帮我们。
And they're gonna need all the brains, we can get out on here.
喂！我都报警了。
Hello? I've called the police.
-玛瑞 -山姆  -是我 -你在干嘛?
-Mary? -Sam.   -Yeah. -What are you doing?
-你到底在干嘛?  -艾拉死了
-Sam, what are you doing?  -Ella died.
我从兽医那回家后，想不到还能去哪儿。
I went home from the vet and I couldn't think of where alse to go.
她属于这里。
She belongs here.
我知道，但你已经不住在这了。
I know, but Sam you don't live here anymore.
你没事吧？你看起来不太好。
Are you alright? You don't look so good.
没事，今天一天绷紧了弦。
Yeah, it's been a rough day all the way around.
我知道，儿子打过电话。
I know, Sammy called.
他还好么？
Is he alright?
他们裁了很多人，
They got hammered,
但他没被裁。
but he got out alive.
那就好。
Good.
好吧，我先回去睡了。
Well, I am going to go back inside and go back to bed.
警报开着，所以别想闯进来。
The alarm is on so don't try and break in.
你自己保重啊。
Take care of yourself, OK?